CLARK VAN OYEN

704 - 31 Elliot St \diamond New Westminster, BC, V3L 5C9 (778) · 709 · 1230 \diamond clark@countable.ca

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Consulting CTO with depth in end-to-end web/cloud product development.

Love developing a shared vision to working prototype, as a methodology to building the best product.

Experience with many aspects related to product: Operations, Test, Automation.

Enjoy finding solutions in diverse stakeholders' negoatiation.

EXPERIENCE

Countable Web Productions Inc.

Owner

December 2008 - present New Westminster, BC

- · Rapid prototyping minimum viable products to gain insight on technical viability and product-market fit.
- · Specialize in unusual web technology deployments, process automation, cloud platform strategy.
- · Developed in-house web product (http://htmlcommentbox.com) now serving over one hundred million visitors per day.
- · Full stack web system design, distributed systems, firmware management, business domain driven design, back-end infrastructure.
- · API integration with mobile apps, sensors / the Internet of Things.
- · Clients list includes Animatic Media (with their clients Nissan, Marvel, Sesame St), Clarius Corporation, Corvus Energy, Kensington Medical, EmerGeo, Altas Realty, Ecotrust Canada, Otono.

Ecotrust Canada

January 2014 - Jan 2016

(Consulting) Chief Technology Officer

Vancouver, BC

- · Developed original core technology of Ecotrust Canada's traceability and electronic monitoring programs, now a seven figure business with dedicated teams.
- · Technology direction for products: monitor emergent technology opportunities; source and mentors technical staff; Contributes technology related strategy and planning, grant and SRED applications, budgeting, licensing, certification and reporting.
- · Design of architecture, technology lifecycles, testing and implementation.

Redback Networks / Ericsson

December 2006 - 2007

ATM Protocol Developer

Burnaby, BC

- · Contributed to the ATM protocol stack in a carrier class router. Developed test coverage tools, worked through a backlog of bugs that spanned other teams modules.
- · Refactored ATM module codebase to address issues found by a static analysis tool.

Convedia / Radisys

December 2005 - 2006

Automation Specialist, SIP Developer

Burnaby, BC

· Developed an automated test manager that configured and utilized a lab full of carrier class computing hardware at night when otherwise idle, to test embedded media server product and report results through flexible web visualizations.

· Wrote the unit test suite for a 3rd party SIP stack integrated by our media server. Contributed to a test harness for the media server product.

SELECTED TOOLS

Languages	Javascript, AWK, HTML, CSS, jade, stylus, OpenGL, MATLAB, TCL, C, C++, Basic (various), ASP, C#, Java, Python, Node.JS, PHP, R, CoffeeScript
Protocols	HTTP, TCP, XML, JSON, SOAP, REST
Databases	MySQL, PostgreSQL, Microsoft SQL, MongoDB, Redis, SQLite
OS / Platforms	(developed under) Windows, Linux, OSX, BSD, lynxos, Android, Arduino
Frameworks	Django, Express, Flask, Wordpress, jQuery, Backbone, Angular, ExtJS, (custom)
Other	GIT, SVN, AWS, Google App Engine, Scrum

SELECTED OPEN SOURCE

Through Ecotrust Canada GitHub

https://github.com/Ecotrust-Canada

- · Hypochondriapp Canadian Open Data Experience hackathon entry, see http://ecotrust-canada.github.io/hypochondriapp/ for a working version.
- · Terratruth A spatial referral management and decision support tool.
- · EM Control Box A remote sensing "firmware" for commercial fishery monitoring (runs in custom embedded linux).

Through Countable GitHub

https://github.com/countable

- · node-dogecoin Maintainer for the Node.JS Dogecoin (cryptocurrency) API.
- · js-fdf Maintainer for the Node.JS FDF implementation.
- · Kinect3D 3d version of Microsoft Kinect API sandbox using WPF 3d objects.
- · (forks) Contributed fixes, features, tests to several bigger OSS projects.

EDUCATION

University of British Columbia B.S. in Computer Science & Physics Completed Co-op, Awarded NSERC	2008
Canadian Association of Physicists Top 15th percentile in CAP Prize Exam	2003
Gulf Islands Film and TV School Classical Animation Certificate	2002

PUBLICATIONS

Operationalizing Open-Source Electronic Monitoring Systems in New England Groundfish Sectors

Fisheries Bycatch: Global Issues and Creative Solutions, Contributor

Interoperable Seafood Traceability Technology Architecture Issues Brief 11.6.15 2014 GFTC, IFT Publication, Contributor